There are 8 basic data types in JavaScript.

number for numbers of any kind: integer or floating-point, integers are limited by ±253.

bigint is for integer numbers of arbitrary length.

string for strings. A string may have zero or more characters, there’s no separate single-character type.

boolean for true/false.

null for unknown values – a standalone type that has a single value null.

undefined for unassigned values – a standalone type that has a single value undefined.

object for more complex data structures.

symbol for unique identifiers.

The typeof operator allows us to see which type is stored in a variable.

Two forms: typeof x or typeof(x).

Returns a string with the name of the type, like "string".

For null returns "object" – this is an error in the language, it’s not actually an object.
